# **MATT MAWSON**

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Philadelphia, PA | matt-mawson.netlify.app | github.com/mawsonm

Software Engineer with a focus on delivering impactful results and a passion for crafting intuitive user experiences. I am a well-organized, meticulous problem solver with 4 years of experience in front-end and back-end development, and a broad range of investment and financial acumen.

#### **SKILLS**

Java	TypeScript	ReactJS	CSS	Python	SQL	
Spring	AWS	Angular	Git	GraphQL	NextJS	

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Application Engineer II, Vanguard

Dec 2023 - Present

- Leading the order generation team with the adoption of React and Next JS.
- Designing and building a scalable AWS system for swap order generation.
- Enhanced Single Portfolio Optimization performance by 50% with a cost-effective and reliable system in AWS.
- Created a maintenance page that permits Run Org and developers to find and remediate issues in the portfolio management tool 75% faster.

#### Application Engineer I, Vanguard

Jul 2022 - Nov 2023

- Developed a variety of order generation workflows related to equity and derivatives, enabling portfolio managers to trade billions of dollars on a weekly basis.
- Utilized AWS Appsync, Lambda, S3, ECS, and SQS to implement cost-effective, scalable systems.
- Wrote hundreds of Jest unit tests in TypeScript, guaranteeing a code coverage rate of 90%.

#### Associate Sr. App Developer, Union Pacific

May 2022 - Jun 2022

- Implemented and maintained an admin user interface for publishing and viewing hydration jobs as well as viewing and updating equipment summary caches.
- Created a customer-facing user-interface that allowed users to create and automate equipment reports, utilizing various Angular Material components, Angular forms, and AG-Grid. Users could select display fields, sorting fields, grouping fields, filter fields, and scheduling criteria. They could also edit, copy, run, disable / enable, and delete reports.

## Junior Application Developer, Union Pacific

Jun 2021 - Apr 2022

- Developed user interfaces with Angular and AG-Grid to aid in root cause analysis, enabling Customer Care & Support to resolve Shipment Management Application issues more than 50% faster.
- Performed back-end maintenance and altered microservices with Spring Boot to obtain data from new data stores, reducing UI inaccuracies by 20%

### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Michigan College of Engineering**

Sep 2017 - May 2021

Bachelor of Science in Industrial & Operations Engineering

- Minor in Computer Science
- Graduated Cum Laude